ANDREA LURIE PAPERS (APAP051) 1967-1986
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
Andrea Lurie Papers1967-1986
nam_apap051
This collection contains materials related to the women's movement and lesbian rights in New York State, especially the Capital Region in the 1970s.
Lurie, Andrea
3.0
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY
Biographical History
Andrea Lurie was active in the womens movement in New Yorks Capital Region including such organizations as the Capital District Women, Women's Counseling Collective, and Tri-City Womens Center.
Scope and Content Information
The collection includes materials related to the women's movement and lesbians with an emphasis on the Capital Region of New York. Andrea Lurie collected photographs from Women's Day in Albany, posters, material related to projects in Albany, correspondence, drafts of manuscripts, and Lurie's own speeches. Records of particular interest are those of the group Capital District Women and the Women's Counseling Collective. Also included are pamphlets, newsletters, journals, and periodicals.
The collection also includes a large number of individual issues of publications. This includes: American Journal of Sociology, Amazon Quarterly, Aphra, Archaeology of Eastern North America, Archeology of the Tocks Island Area, Aurora, Bulletin of the Archaeological Society of New Jersey, The Chesopiean: A Journal of North American Archaeology, Complaints and Disorders: The Sexual Politics of Sickness, Country Women, Cowrie, Double X, Dyke, Dykes and Gorgons, Eastern States Archaeological Federation, Electric Circle, Every Woman, The Furies Lesbian/Feminist Monthly, Hecate, Her-self Women's News Journal, Journal of Family History, No More Fun and Games: Journal of Female Liberation, Journal of the National Association of Women Deans and Counselors, Lavender Woman, The Lesbian Feminist, Majority Report, Man in the Northeast, 13th Moon, Motive, The New York State Wampum Collection: The Case for the Integrity of Cultural Treasures, Off Our Backs: A Women's News Journal, Paid My Dues: A Monthly Journal of Women and Music, The Political Economy of Women, Prime Time, Signs: Journal of Women in Culture and Society, Speak Out: A Feminist Journal The Suffragette, Symposium on the Religion of the Eastern Woodland Indians, We Have Seen You There, Women, Women in the Struggle for Liberation, Women's Rights Law Reporter, The Archaeological Society of New Jersey, The Lesbian Connection, The Talking Leaf, The Spoken Woman, The Second Wave, and Trans Action.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection has no series, arranged alphabetically.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives by Andrea Lurie. 1994 June
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Subject and Genre Headings
Women; Human Sexuality and Gender Identity; Albany, New York; Lurie, Andrea; Women's rights -- New York (State); Homosexuality -- Law and legislation -- New York (State); Posters; Minutes; Speeches
Container List
- "An Army of Lovers Shall Not Fail", Undated (Flat-file 1)
- Archaeological Conferences, 1970; 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Capital District Women, Organizational Records, ca. 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Capital District Women, Small Group, ca. 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Collage, Production "Because I Said So," Interart Theatre, Women's Interart Center, New York City, Playwright Myrna Lamb, Photographer Jill Lynne, Undated (Flat-file 2)
- Expensive People, a Screenplay by Eleanor Perry, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- "Make History - with Your Vote! Judge Nanette Dembitz for Court of Appeals, Elect the First Woman to New York's Highest Court", ca. 1972 (Flat-file 3)
- Miscellaneous, 1971; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- New York State Women's Meeting, First, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Papers and Articles, ca. 1967-1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "Sisterhood: Make It Real, Woman's Studio Collective, New Paltz", Undated (Flat-file 4)
- "Speak Out: a Feminist Journal," Susan B. Anthony Cover Art, Poster, 1973 (Flat-file 5)
- Speeches, Andrea Lurie, 1973; Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Susan Saxe and Assata Shakur Benefit, Sponsored by the Women's Defense Committee, March 20, Undated (Flat-file 6)
- Talking Leaf, Publication of the Los Angeles Indian Center, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Tri-City Women's Center Newsletter, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Women of Tennis, Calendar, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Women's Counseling Collective, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Women's Day, Albany, Photographs, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Women's Day, Washington Park, Albany, August 26, Undated (Flat-file 7)